A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Tourism Corporation, 2000-2007.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Minutes of the Virginia Tourism Corporation,
2000-2007.
The Library of Virginia
44079
Virginia Tourism Corporation.
.2 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
Accession 44079 transferred by the Virginia Tourism Corportion, 8 Dec 2008.
Historical Information
The Virginia Tourism Authority is a political subdivision of the Commonwealth of Virginia, authorized to do business as the Virginia Tourism Corporation. The Virginia Tourism Corporation was created on July 1, 1999, and prior to that was the Division of Tourism within the Virginia Economic Development Partnership. The Virginia Tourism Corporation is tasked with promoting, advertising and marketing Virginia's many tourist attractions and coordinating with other private and public efforts to do the same. The corporation develops and implements programs to support, maintain and expand the Commonwealth's travel market and motion picture industry in order to increase visitor expenditures, tax revenues and motion picture production.
The Governor appoints the Executive Director who serves as President and chief executive officer of the Virginia Tourism Corporation. The 15 member Board of Directors includes the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Secretary of Finance, Secretary of Natural Resources, and 12 other member appointed by the Governor and confirmed by the General Assembly. The Board serves in an advisory capacity to the Executive Director, who serves as the Board's secretary-treasurer.
The Virginia Tourism Corporation is headquartered in Richmond and operates ten welcome centers across the state and the Capitol Bell Tower in Richmond to provide information to people traveling in Virginia. The Virginia Film Office is part of the Corporation and works to attract film and video production to the state of Virginia, as well as support the indigenous production industry.
Scope and Content
Minutes, 2000-2007, document the meetings, activities, discussions, policy decisions and recommendations of the Board of Directors of the Virginia Tourism Corporation (VTC). This series also includes Committee meeting minutes, 2001-2003; copies of the Virginia Tourism Corporation Bylaws and the Virginia Tourism Authority Act; and two publications - This Year Discover Jefferon's Virginia, 1997 and VTC Resource Book, 2007-2008. Dates of some of the materials falls outside of the dates of the minutes.
Contents List
- Minutes of the Virginia Tourism Corporation, 2000-2007.
  - Minutes, 2000. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2001. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2002. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2003. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2004. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2005. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2006. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2007. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bylaws, 2000. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Tourism Authority Act 2008. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Publications, 1997; 2007-2008. (Box 1)